Alberto Morón Hernández

alberto.moronh@gmail.com

albertomh.com

github.com/albertomh

Software engineer with 5 years' experience at ease across the stack. Equally happy building serverless backends routing tens of thousands of requests per second, creating responsive frontends, or designing database schemas and exposing them via well-documented RESTful APIs.

Trusted to make choices about the technology used in key projects and to interview & manage junior members of the team.

Key technologies: Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, Docker, JavaScript & TypeScript, Angular, SCSS, AWS, Cloudflare, Linux, Python, Bash, git.

Experience

Software engineer at Wealth Club

February 2019 - April 2022

One half of a two-person team developing & running all technology for Wealth Club, a venture capital broker with £800M AUM.

Built a caching layer that enabled a legacy site to withstand 10x traffic spikes, serving 4.9 million requests per month. Supported organic traffic growing +94% YoY. Wrote serverless Cloudflare Workers to improve a Django-based CMS, making the site 3.5x cheaper to run, increasing our SEO score and boosting conversion rates.

Co-led interviews for software engineers, testers, and DevOps roles. Onboarded, trained, and managed workload for two new junior colleagues.

Architected and built an intranet using Spring (Java), Angular (TypeScript), Docker, and PostgreSQL. Centralised control and reduced reliance on 3rd-party services.

Phased out manual testing practices by writing automated unit & integration tests. Used BrowserStack, Selenium, and Gherkin for BDD.

Performed attribution modelling to understand user behaviour in response to marketing campaigns, helping to reduce the cost per lead.

Halved the monthly Cloudflare bill by removing redundant services and refactoring to use more efficient alternatives from the same vendor, minimising migration costs.

Sped up database queries by an order of magnitude when I replaced inefficient ORM use with SQL functions.

Networking on-prem & cloud: AWS VPC, DNS, FortiGate, DHCP, SIP telephony.

Documented code and processes, writing playbooks for common issues.

Software developer at Nomensa

June 2017 - February 2019

Built a learning platform for the NHS as part of a cross-functional team of UX researchers, designers, fellow developers, and client stakeholders.

Pioneered JavaScript service workers to enable the solution to work offline inside operating theatres.

Created data visualisation & forecasting tools in Python (numpy, matplotlib) to monitor application health and provide insights into user behaviour.

Reduced technical debt and wrote documentation for legacy projects in the energy, healthcare, and charity sectors.

Open-source contributions

Nacar (Python 3, Bash) github.com/albertomh/Nacar

Nacar is a tool to create interactive text-based interfaces, combining my interests in metaprogramming, computational approaches to language, and improving the Developer Experience. It features full test coverage & extensive documentation.

Exodus (Java, Spring, SQL) github.com/albertomh/Exodus

Exodus is a database migration runner I have created for Spring web applications. It is light (~7 kb) and simple to integrate into existing systems. Supported by a suite of unit and integration tests.

Education

University of Manchester | BA (Hons) Linguistics & English Literature (1st) 2014 - 2017

My dissertation focused on computationally paraphrasing verbal metonymy: refining algorithms to understand certain English-language constructs. Supported by Amazon via an AWS Educate grant & awarded the 2017 Q-Step prize. arxiv.org/abs/1709.06162

Modules included: Symbolic Logic; Semantics; Forensic Linguistics; Typology.

University of Massachusetts, Amherst (USA) | Comp. Linguistics (88%, Dean's List) 2016, Year abroad

Honed my Python skills with an emphasis on NLP tasks. At hackathons around the Pioneer Valley I learned to use third-party APIs and write code as part of a team.

Modules included: Computational Linguistics; Syntax; Language & Cognition.

King's College Madrid (Spain) | GCSEs and A-Levels 2000 - 2014